http://probinso.dyn-o-saur.com

Personal Statement

I am a graduate student at Oregon Health and Sciences University. After completing my BS at Western Washington University, and my 4 years industry expirience, I have developed strong interests in cryptography, statistical computing, and programming languages. I am a very quick study, as I have adopted a new or tool-set in nearly every challenge I have taken on. My interest in teaching and writing has granted me strong communication skills, and solid background.

Language Experience :

* Python Julia Scala, Figaro Perl Ada C, C++ R $\mathbb{E}T_EX$

Education _

Oregon Health Science University

CSLU

MSc Computer Science 2016 - present

Courses :

Machine Learning Statistical Methods Information Retrieval Univariate Statistical Analysis Computing Ethics Analysis of Sequences

Extra Carricular

MOOC/Bootcamp

Coursera / EdX / Stanford Online Hack Oregon

Courses :

Functional Programming in Scala Agile Machine Learning PPAML Summer Program Applied Cryptography

Western Washington University

Computer Science

Computer Science BS Mathematics Minor Sept. 2007 - June 2012

Electives :

Homomorphic Encryption Systems Cryptography & Elliptic Curves Artificial Intelligence Natural Language Processing Functional Programming

Computer Graphics Computer Architecture Elementary Real Analysis Linear Algebra I/II Abstract Algebra

Work Experience

Independent C&W Energy

- Contractor/Consultant

Nov. 2015 - present

Authored educational material in light pollution on economy, biology, and technology Light classification engine, custom photo image processing tools, and mathematical models Developed a memoizing database-interface for caching computationally expensive operations

June 2016 - Sept. 2016

Worked to support large, custom, memory mapped, data store for demographic analysis PDXCodeGuild June 2016

Developed and taught introductory python course material for coding boot-camp

Setup infrastructure in AWS to enable secure sustainable workflow for remote company Provided hands on training in Python and R to industry professionals

Languages Used: Python, R, AWS, PostgreSQL, Perl, C++

Galois Inc. - Research Engineer

April 2014 - Dec 2015

Contributed to PPAML, Overseas Voting Foundation, Safeware, Robot Fast Track
Developed technologies and workflows to enable evaluator work for DARPA programs
Produced biannual quantitative and qualitative reports on for DARPA and language developers
Participated in programs sharing new technologies to research and industry professionals

Languages Used : Python, Scala, Figaro, Chimpy, Docker

EMC² Isilon Storage - Software Development Engineer Dec. 2012 - July 2013

Brought to schedule a lagging anchor release feature in approximately 5 months

Designed and developed password manager to support Data At Rest Encryption

Wrote unit tests using libcheck to attain > 80% code coverage

Languages Used : C, C++, Python, SQLite

Computer Science Dept. - Mentors Program Director/Mentor Sept. 2009 - March 2012
Provided safe environment for training and instruction of students and mentors
Ran student/faculty meetings to project future program responsibilities
Wrote comprehensive quarterly reports, and tools for automatic report generation
Languages Used: Ada, C++, Scheme, R

Neato Projects

Clurak - Information Retrieval Cluster/Rank Demo Harness flask, gensim, Python Relivance Vector Machine with kernel and platt support Julia Sad Clown Research Group gh-pages, pelican, blog Sensor Systems and Light Pollution Analysis aws, sklearn, scipy, PonyORM, Python Gene Data Breast Cancer Drug Predictor R, caret Gradient Descent on Arbitrary Degree Polynomials Julia Probabilistic-Program Profiler and Evaluator Harness SLURM, PonyORM, Python Distributed Fully Homomorphic Encryption System Hadoop, Python Concurrent Elliptic Curve Cryptography Module Erlang, Sagemath Multilingual Analysis of Subordinating and Coordinating Conjunctions R, Perl AdaRailz Concurrent Model Train Control System Ada Fractal Art Generator & Image Manipulation Program C#